<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Try Flink on Apache Flink</title>
    <link>//localhost/flink/flink-docs-master/docs/try-flink/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Try Flink on Apache Flink</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="//localhost/flink/flink-docs-master/docs/try-flink/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>First steps</title>
      <link>//localhost/flink/flink-docs-master/docs/try-flink/local_installation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost/flink/flink-docs-master/docs/try-flink/local_installation/</guid>
      <description>First steps # Welcome to Flink! :)
Flink is designed to process continuous streams of data at a lightning fast pace. This short guide will show you how to download the latest stable version of Flink, install, and run it. You will also run an example Flink job and view it in the web UI.
Downloading Flink # Note: Flink is also available as a Docker image. Flink runs on all UNIX-like environments, i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fraud Detection with the DataStream API</title>
      <link>//localhost/flink/flink-docs-master/docs/try-flink/datastream/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost/flink/flink-docs-master/docs/try-flink/datastream/</guid>
      <description>Fraud Detection with the DataStream API # Apache Flink offers a DataStream API for building robust, stateful streaming applications. It provides fine-grained control over state and time, which allows for the implementation of advanced event-driven systems. In this step-by-step guide you&amp;rsquo;ll learn how to build a stateful streaming application with Flink&amp;rsquo;s DataStream API.
What Are You Building? # Credit card fraud is a growing concern in the digital age. Criminals steal credit card numbers by running scams or hacking into insecure systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Real Time Reporting with the Table API</title>
      <link>//localhost/flink/flink-docs-master/docs/try-flink/table_api/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost/flink/flink-docs-master/docs/try-flink/table_api/</guid>
      <description>Real Time Reporting with the Table API # Apache Flink offers a Table API as a unified, relational API for batch and stream processing, i.e., queries are executed with the same semantics on unbounded, real-time streams or bounded, batch data sets and produce the same results. The Table API in Flink is commonly used to ease the definition of data analytics, data pipelining, and ETL applications.
What Will You Be Building?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flink Operations Playground</title>
      <link>//localhost/flink/flink-docs-master/docs/try-flink/flink-operations-playground/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost/flink/flink-docs-master/docs/try-flink/flink-operations-playground/</guid>
      <description>Flink Operations Playground # There are many ways to deploy and operate Apache Flink in various environments. Regardless of this variety, the fundamental building blocks of a Flink Cluster remain the same, and similar operational principles apply.
In this playground, you will learn how to manage and run Flink Jobs. You will see how to deploy and monitor an application, experience how Flink recovers from Job failure, and perform everyday operational tasks like upgrades and rescaling.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
