<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>High Availability on Apache Flink</title>
    <link>//localhost/flink/flink-docs-master/docs/deployment/ha/</link>
    <description>Recent content in High Availability on Apache Flink</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="//localhost/flink/flink-docs-master/docs/deployment/ha/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Overview</title>
      <link>//localhost/flink/flink-docs-master/docs/deployment/ha/overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost/flink/flink-docs-master/docs/deployment/ha/overview/</guid>
      <description>High Availability # JobManager High Availability (HA) hardens a Flink cluster against JobManager failures. This feature ensures that a Flink cluster will always continue executing your submitted jobs.
JobManager High Availability # The JobManager coordinates every Flink deployment. It is responsible for both scheduling and resource management.
By default, there is a single JobManager instance per Flink cluster. This creates a single point of failure (SPOF): if the JobManager crashes, no new programs can be submitted and running programs fail.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ZooKeeper HA Services</title>
      <link>//localhost/flink/flink-docs-master/docs/deployment/ha/zookeeper_ha/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost/flink/flink-docs-master/docs/deployment/ha/zookeeper_ha/</guid>
      <description>ZooKeeper HA Services # Flink&amp;rsquo;s ZooKeeper HA services use ZooKeeper for high availability services.
Flink leverages ZooKeeper for distributed coordination between all running JobManager instances. ZooKeeper is a separate service from Flink, which provides highly reliable distributed coordination via leader election and light-weight consistent state storage. Check out ZooKeeper&amp;rsquo;s Getting Started Guide for more information about ZooKeeper. Flink includes scripts to bootstrap a simple ZooKeeper installation.
Configuration # In order to start an HA-cluster you have to configure the following configuration keys:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kubernetes HA Services</title>
      <link>//localhost/flink/flink-docs-master/docs/deployment/ha/kubernetes_ha/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost/flink/flink-docs-master/docs/deployment/ha/kubernetes_ha/</guid>
      <description>Kubernetes HA Services # Flink&amp;rsquo;s Kubernetes HA services use Kubernetes for high availability services.
Kubernetes high availability services can only be used when deploying to Kubernetes. Consequently, they can be configured when using standalone Flink on Kubernetes or the native Kubernetes integration
Prerequisites # In order to use Flink&amp;rsquo;s Kubernetes HA services you must fulfill the following prerequisites:
Kubernetes &amp;gt;= 1.9. Service account with permissions to create, edit, delete ConfigMaps.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
