<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Resource Providers on Apache Flink</title>
    <link>//localhost/flink/flink-docs-master/zh/docs/deployment/resource-providers/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Resource Providers on Apache Flink</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="//localhost/flink/flink-docs-master/zh/docs/deployment/resource-providers/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Native Kubernetes</title>
      <link>//localhost/flink/flink-docs-master/zh/docs/deployment/resource-providers/native_kubernetes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost/flink/flink-docs-master/zh/docs/deployment/resource-providers/native_kubernetes/</guid>
      <description>Native Kubernetes # This page describes how to deploy Flink natively on Kubernetes.
Getting Started # This Getting Started section guides you through setting up a fully functional Flink Cluster on Kubernetes.
Introduction # Kubernetes is a popular container-orchestration system for automating computer application deployment, scaling, and management. Flink&amp;rsquo;s native Kubernetes integration allows you to directly deploy Flink on a running Kubernetes cluster. Moreover, Flink is able to dynamically allocate and de-allocate TaskManagers depending on the required resources because it can directly talk to Kubernetes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>YARN</title>
      <link>//localhost/flink/flink-docs-master/zh/docs/deployment/resource-providers/yarn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost/flink/flink-docs-master/zh/docs/deployment/resource-providers/yarn/</guid>
      <description>Apache Hadoop YARN # Getting Started # This Getting Started section guides you through setting up a fully functional Flink Cluster on YARN.
Introduction # Apache Hadoop YARN is a resource provider popular with many data processing frameworks. Flink services are submitted to YARN&amp;rsquo;s ResourceManager, which spawns containers on machines managed by YARN NodeManagers. Flink deploys its JobManager and TaskManager instances into such containers.
Flink can dynamically allocate and de-allocate TaskManager resources depending on the number of processing slots required by the job(s) running on the JobManager.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
